modelmanagement.com 2019-12-29

# Privacy policy | Model Management

### How we handle any personal data you give us

When you join modelmanagement.com we want you to know exactly what happens with your data, so you can have complete confidence in being one of our valued and much loved members.

The information that we request from you is for one purpose only, to improve your experience and help you get the most from being a member of modelmanagement.com and to use our platform in a business to business way with your peers. To give you even more peace of mind, we look after your data in the right way and never share it with any 3rd parties.

### What data do we collect?

This list includes some mandatory data which we request from you, in addition to optional data which you can enter into your account if you would like others to know more about your professional abilities.

  * Name and/or company name
  * Email address
  * Location
  * Gender
  * Website or portfolio link, if you have one
  * Password which is encrypted
  * Date of birth (parental or legal guardian consent is required for any user under 16 years old) 
  * Details of your transactions on our site
  * Date when you signed up, your last login, uploaded images, followed another user, loved, liked or favourited an image or another user

Additional data only for model members

  * Ethnicity, nationality, hair and eye colour, height, shoe size, bust size, waist size, hips size, dress size
  * Languages spoken
  * Modeling categories and disciplines that suit your look
  * Your favourite places to connect with with people
  * Date when you apply to castings, or accepted/declined a booking
  * Details of payments made through our site, reviews, comments etc
  * Free text area called "About me" where you can leave any relevant professional information about yourself
  * Phone number
  * Social media links
  * Uploaded images

Additional data only for model agencies, photographers, brands and other industry professional members

  * Visual media industry sector
  * Free text area called "About me" where you can leave any relevant professional information about yourself
  * Phone number
  * Social media links
  * Uploaded images

### Which providers do we share your data with? 

Companies we use to connect with to provide services through our website. For example if you upgrade to Premium we connect with worldwide payment companies such as Paypal to handle to the online payment securely. Click on the individual company names to view their privacy policies.

Analytics - GTM with [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html)
    Cookies and usage data
Marketing - [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) and [Twitter](https://business.twitter.com/en/help/ads-policies/other-policy-requirements/policies-for-conversion-tracking-and-tailored-audiences.html) pixels
    Cookies and usage data
Advertising - [Google DFP](https://policies.google.com/privacy)
    Cookies and usage data
Handling payments – [Recurly](https://recurly.com/legal/privacy), [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) and [Ebanx](https://business.ebanx.com/en/privacy-policy)
    Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
SMS - [Twilio](https://www.twilio.com/legal/privacy)
    Phone number, usage data
Managing contacts and sending messages - [Sendy](https://sendy.co/privacy-policy), [SES](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/), [Sendgrid](https://sendgrid.com/policies/privacy/), [Mailchimp](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/), [Mailgun](https://www.mailgun.com/privacy-policy)
    Email address, usage data
Support and live chat - [Zendesk](https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/)
    Email address, cookies, usage data
Access to third-party account. These are companies you can decide to use on our website to make certain tasks simpler. For example if you decide to sign up to our site with Facebook, or if you decide to invite your personal contacts to join our site via your own email database.
    [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update) \- About me, birthday, city, email address, website
    [Google](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and [Yahoo](https://policies.yahoo.com/xa/en/yahoo/privacy/index.htm) \- Contacts
SPAM protection - [Akismet](https://akismet.com/tos/) and [Google reCAPTCHA](https://policies.google.com/privacy)
    Various types of data as specified in the privacy policy of the service
Interaction with external social networks and platforms - [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) Like button and social widgets, [Pinterest](https://policy.pinterest.com/privacy-policy) and [Google +1](https://policies.google.com/privacy)
    Cookies and usage data
Content performance and features testing (A/B testing) - [Google optimize](https://policies.google.com/privacy)
    Cookies and usage data

### Which 3rd parties do we share your data with?

We do will not share your data with any third parties, unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.

### How long do we keep your data?

Your data will be kept as long as you are a user of our site and have not requested that your account and data to be erased.

### Where is it stored? 

All data is stored on our secure European based servers

### Do we have lawful reasons why we need this data?

The lawful reasons why we need this data are legitimate interests pursued by the company, as established by the GDPR (Article 6).

### What do we do with this information?

Analyse user activity to improve our service

Provide a high quality and ultimately useful user experience throughout our site and email communication

We may notify you by email, phone or SMS with important information of relevance to your account, for example if you have been invited to a casting or if a member has messaged you. In addition if another user has liked, loved your images or followed you, or with changes and updates to our site, promotional offers, surveys, tips, news etc. 

### IP addresses and Cookies

IP address is stored temporarily for security and spam prevention.

modelmanagement.com uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record session information, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, record past activity at a site in order to provide better service when visitors return to our site, customise Web page content based on visitors' browser type or other information that the visitor sends.

Cookies are text files that are either temporarily stored in the random access memory or on the hard drive of your computer. They generally serve for offering you the services of modelmanagement.com within your personal settings of each new session, which basically means to give you a better and faster experience more in tune with what you like to see. Cookies are partly stored permanently on your hard drive. You may prevent this by setting your browser accordingly, however you may notice that our website does not run as fast and in the same way to what you would expect. 

### Technical security

We will report any data breaches and security issues to the data protection authority within 72 hours of discovery. We will also notify by email any users who are directly affected by this breach.

### How you can control the use and display of your information?

All data that we gather is used to give you and other users the best possible experience on our website.

You have the right to edit or erase certain information about you on your account, but this may result in our site being less useful for you.

You have the right for your account and information about you to be erased from our site. You can find this by logging into your account and visiting Edit profile and by clicking the link: Request your account to be deleted.

If you want to opt in or out of the emails we send you, these can be changed in the Edit my profile section of your account. Certain important emails may still be sent to you, for example if you've forgotten your password, or if we update our Terms and Conditions or Privacy Policy.

You can request to see details of any personal information which we hold about you. If you would like to see this information, please contact us at: privacy@modelmanagement.com. You will need to provide proof of your identity and we may charge a fee to provide this information. Requests of information will take up to 30 days.

### Changes to this privacy policy

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time. This page will show a notice that changes have been made. If a user objects to the updated Privacy Policy, they should request for their account to be erased and personal data removed.

We hope that this Privacy Policy answers any questions that you may have. If you have any further questions, feel free to contact us directly here by email at: privacy@modelmanagement.com

### Contact us

Creative Talent Evolution S.L..  
Moll de Barcelona, WTC  
08039 Barcelona  
Spain  
V.A.T. NUMBER: ESB66936352  
Company Registration Number: T45912-F118-B502829  
Email: privacy@modelmanagement.com
